sat down in front of my PC and replayed dishonored a lot of people don't realize it's a tribute to the
Post-Industrial novel Genre now. I just made that up, but it does sound like something that could be true. I
Relived the order I've reviewed bioshock
I've reviewed Assassin's creed, but what would it sound like if I reviewed all three at the same time (unintelligible)
Dishonored has a little bit of all three
But it's nothing like any of them the game starts with a woman reading a letter
She has sent her most trusted servant a man named Corvo on a diplomatic mission to ask for help
There is a plague that is pretty much killing the entire nation
Obviously Corvo hasn't done any of this years went down south and spent the entire budget on booze and cocaine
You play as Corvo, obviously, he is the empress bodyguard and right now he's on a boat
I think this opening is great it really prepares the player for what's about to come as about
60% of the game is just sitting in a boat waiting, the boat goes up an elevator and now you're here then the
Empress daughter runs up to you
And ask if you want to play hide and seek
Obviously your answers is no you have been on a four month vacation that requires a lot of paperwork, but first
Corvo needs to deliver the message that the other nations...
wrote
So you walk up to the empress and she's like, "Thank God you're back, what news do you bring?"
"We're not gonna help you cuz you guys suck dick from the king of the Tibetan republic"
"Corvo, I'm not mad. I'm just disappointed"
But corvo gets lucky because the queen gets attacked
But then he gets not so lucky because the empress kind of dies and the daughter gets kidnapped
And he gets the blame so, he spends six month in prison and gets tortured by these fellas, the lord regent and the high overseer
They keep telling him to confess to the murder, "Yes, we kill her, but it was for a good cause we need strong leadership now"
"Also, she wasn't that smart she gave a very important diplomatic mission to a guy that can't talk"
Corvo agrees and he's trying to confess, but he can't because he's a silent protagonist
But what's this a suspicious loaf of bread, Corvo's sucks it up
Under the bread is a key, and after you get that key and leave your prison cell the game actually starts
We find out right away that there are two ways to play the game
The normal way kill everything that's in your way, or the way that is not for casual scum
sneak and don't kill anyone, that even goes for the assassination targets
We get later on I obviously went with the don't kill anyone way because I have a reputation of being 'hardcore'
Corvo leaves the prison and there is Samuel and his...
boat
Hello, I'm samuel. I'm the only not evil person in this entire nation
entire, nation
He takes Corvo to a hidden place where we meet the royalist
It's a secret society that...
Wants to take down the lord regent and put the daughter of the empress on the throne
"Hello I represent nobility"
"And I represent people that lift," they give you missions and work as a mission hub you can also walk around and talk to
Them find out if they are evil and are going to betray you it's pretty obvious
I mean look at him you meet this guy with his kooky inventions and his crazy stuff
He gives you gear and upgrades for gear these are completely useless to me
So there's that later when corvo goes to sleep. He wakes up in this weird world. "Hello
I'm a god and I'm going to give you super powers
Thank jesus you're a silent protagonist other people usually bombard me with questions right about now" you get the teleport ability and they see through walls
Ability, but as the game goes on you can upgrade and get new abilities
Uh... these are completely useless to me, so there's that. Your first mission is to take out the overseer, that guy
So first you're on a boat
Then you walk towards this place, then you meet the plague victim for the first time and by Plague Victim. I actually mean zombie. Yes
Dishonored is a mix between bioshock. Assassin's Creed and resident evil
but the Disonored actually revolutionizes the Zombie Genre
By not being early access. As you sneak around you overhear guard's conversations usually it's completely useless
"Hey, Mike, I'm a dick," "haha me too." But sometimes it can actually be very helpful a bit too helpful
"Hey, Andrew, if you were the queen's ex bodyguard and just gotten a teleport ability how would you take out the high overseer in a non-lethal way?"
"Funny you should ask, I've been thinking about that all day"
So you make the overseer fall asleep then you drag him to this chair and brand him a heretic which also means he's exiled
This is clearly a stuck communication error and should be easy to fix
But then you remember that she has been empress for 12 years and it all makes sense
Second mission, "My twin brothers are evil, please take them out, right now they're at a 'bathhouse'"
Wink-wink Nudge-nudge, Wink-wink
Nudge-Nudge
So corvo is off to the whorehouse
But first you need to find a non-lethal way to take them out, so you go to this gangster
"I can take out the pendleton's in a non-Lethal way, but first you have to do something for me
There's an art man at the brothel. I am actually a very big fan of art
Don't tell anyone I'm a gangster, but he said that the rococo Style was dead
Yeah, fuck that guy, okay?
I want you to torture him until he changes his mind," so you go to the brothel
And you 'torture' Wink-wink nudge-nudge the guy until he changes his mind, "Okay that's fantastic
You Wanna know what I'm going to do with the pendeltens?
I'm gonna cut off their tongues, and I'm gonna shave your heads, and I'm gonna force them to work in the mine"
That, that sounds a bit extreme
I'm starting to think these non-lethal ways are way worse than the kill ways
And I don't get why you get the good ending if you don't kill anyone
Also, you rescued the princess there, but not really relevant anyways next mission
Go capture the inventor guy so you go capture the inventor guy
And he says, "Go capture this woman Suka," next mission more boat you are supposed to find and kill a woman at this
Masquerade party
but you don't know what she actually looks like when you enter the building a guy walks up to you and tells you that he
Loves this woman, and if you give her to him, so he can keep her forever she will never reappear again
Sounds very disturbing , but oh well
He doesn't tell you what she looks like and I have no idea what to do right now. Shit, fuck, Come on, fuck, god
fuck (music)
So you just have to talk to this person and she pretty much tells you
This is the easiest mission ever yeah
So we're finally ready to take down Lord regent first you travel by boat (REEEEEE) to the palace
We saw at the start of the game then you visit a radio tower inside the palace and the guy there tells you that
Inside the Lord regents room there is a recording that is so awful he will never be allowed to rule again
Corvo gets the tape then he puts it in the player and it gets broadcast to the entire nation "Dunwall pizza palace," "hello
This is the lord regent
I would like a kids pizza meal
And I would like the beyblades not the doll," "anything extra on your pizza?"
"Yes...
Pineapple,"(pineapple isn't that bad) (unless if it's on pizza then it is VERY BAD) the Lord regent is promptly arrested. "We did it yay. Yay
We did it," Corvo drinks a victory drink and it's poison he goes down faster than you can say 'wow didn't see that one coming'
But he doesn't die he only falls asleep because samuel saves his life. He puts the body on a (sigh)...
Boat and Corvo gets captured by the guys that the lord regent hired to kill the empress
"I recognize those tattoos on your hand bodyguard
I've met him too, most pretentious god I've ever met you can't just do something like that and act like it's normal"
They throw Corvo in a hole and put a...wooden pallet over the hole
Corvo Escapes the hole that had a wooden pallet over it
Get back to the others. He needs a key but the master assassin is standing in his way
"Ahhh, It's time for a battle that no one has seen with the human eyes a duel beyond the realms of man a
Fight-- did you just fucking leave are- are you actually doing this? are you for real right now?
Really?
Asshole," you get back to the place where they hid and you find out everyone you knew and loved has been brutally murdered
Except for these two guys and samuel you find out where they went and you go after them to take revenge
For a place with so beautiful architecture they sure do make ugly lighthouses
Corvo travels to the top of Lighthouse to have his revenge
And they're all dead the buff guy poisoned them they died a quick and painless death yeah
I can't be dealing this the army guy hands Corvo the key and Corvo jumps off the lighthouse and dies the end
My biggest problem with the game is that people walk around and sing drunken sailor?
I think they should have added more folk if you're interested in dihonored you should probably check out another review and
That's the Killian experience. What game should I do next
Garbage reviews is a series and you could check out the previous
episodes
Also, they just announced dishonored 2. So that's pretty fantastic also if you haven't clicked away the video
Yeah, you can like it
Haven't eaten sold it in forever